<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LRSlab@CityU</title>
    <link>http://lrslab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LRSlab@CityU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://lrslab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://lrslab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lrslab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>We have open positions for research postgraduate students (PhD program). Please send your CV and your github account to PI&amp;rsquo;s email if interested.
update on 2025/05/21 Link to heading We have PhD positions open for applications. The successful candidates will work on the following projects:
Genetics related research on hybrid incompatibility between C. briggsae and C. nigoni. Method development for DNA/RNA modification finding using nanopore sequencing. The basic requirements for the candidates are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LRSLab@CityU</title>
      <link>http://lrslab.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lrslab.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Our group&amp;rsquo;s current research interest: Link to heading Developing applications/pipelines to accommodate the Nanopore DNA/RNA sequencing platform. Developing toolkits for genome assembly, scaffolding, finishing, improvement and comparative analysis. Studying the nucleotide modifications (like m6A) in RNAs (including viral/prokaryotic/eukaryotic RNAs). Mechanism of hybrid incompatibilities between Canorhabditis briggsae and nigoni. DNA modifications in acute myeloid leukemia (AML). Open positions: Link to heading Research student (PhD) position on bioinformatics. Research student (PhD) position on Canorhabditis based genetic research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>http://lrslab.github.io/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lrslab.github.io/members/</guid>
      <description>LI Runsheng (李润生), DVM, PhD.
Assistant Professor, PI Department of Infectious Diseases and Public Health, City University of Hong Kong ZHANG Yiwen, PhD student, Hybrid incompatibility between C. briggsae and C. nigoni. GUO Zhihao, PhD student, Developing RNA modification calling methods in Nanopore direct-RNA sequencing. LIU Xudong, Research assistant, Developing genome scaffolding methods using DNA modification signals. SHAO Yanwen, PhD student, Applications in long read RNAseq sequencing. LI Ke, PhD student, Application and analysis of non-conding repetitive sequences using both long and short read sequencing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://lrslab.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lrslab.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications in recent five years: Link to heading 2025 Link to heading Lu, B., Guo, Z., Liu, X., Ni, Y., Xu, L., Huang, J., Li, T., Feng, T., Li, R.# and Deng, X.#, 2025. Comprehensive comparison of the third-generation sequencing tools for bacterial 6mA profiling. Nature Communications, 16(1), p.3982. (#co-corresponding author) Liu, T., Liu, X., Dai, X., Huang, J., Li, R., Wang, L. and Wang, X., 2025. Characterization of the ribosomal RNA methylase gene erm (A) and its promoter mutation in Campylobacter coli from chicken cecum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>http://lrslab.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lrslab.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>Hammerhead - [Python] - Hammerhead is a pipeline for the detection of bacterial DNA modifications and fix modification induced assembly error from Nanopore R10.4.1 reads. Published in Genome Research, 2024
nanoCEM -[Python] - The nanopore current events magnifier (nanoCEM) is a python command line to facilitate the analysis of DNA/RNA modification sites by visualizing statistical features of current events. Published in NARGAB, 2024
Giraffe - [Python] - Giraffe is used for long read QC, can be used to calculate and visualize basic statistics for nanopore/pacbio long reads, including observed/estimated read quality; gc bias for reads; homopolymer accuracy and others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
